So, what stock is better? Manulife or
Sun Life? We will see.
Um so, I own Manulife. I own 149 shares.
I'm looking to invest more money into
insurance because for all those
categories where I don't own a lot of
stock in. And then on March 23rd, I
thought it was a time to strike and I
bought I got up to 149 shares at this
point. So, dividend-wise, and I care
about the dividends. I'll be I'll be
upfront. Dividends are huge to me. As
well as getting into different asset
classes that I'm not usually in. So, I'm
more protected in the market. So, on the
year, Manulife will pay me $166.88.
And if you divide that by 12, that's
$13.90 per month. Manulife pays me. Now
again, they pay quarterly.
But if they did pay monthly, it would be
1390.
I've been asking myself, did I make the
right decision? Because we also have Sun
Life Financial here in Canada,
as well as Manulife. Now, there's other
ones as well that I haven't really
looked into too much and I probably
should. Uh but for now,
the two big ones that I see are Sun Life
and Manulife. How do they compare? How
do they compare dividend-wise?
Let's have a look. Let's just go to
their website first of all. So, we'll go
to Manulife.
Now, what do they do?
I've clicked products and Canada. Uh now
again, both of these companies have a
have money coming in from Asia as well.
They've got clients there, been doing
very well overseas. They also operate in
the United States and Canada and it
looks like all over the world. So, they
are both growing companies. But let's
investigate. So, as far as products,
let's go. So, we have insurance.
It's not what we have in life, but who
we have that matters. I agree. So, it
looks like they have health. Let's click
that. So, they have health and dental
insurance, disability insurance,
critical illness insurance. So, there's
something called the Manulife synergy,
which is a three-in-one life,
disability, and critical illness
protection. Oh, there's the health and
dental, disability insurance, long-term
care insurance, critical illness
insurance, like I said. We have term
life insurance, permanent life
insurance, and the synergy thing. Cover
me, family life, business term, travel
insurance. So, we have traveling
Canadians, students, and visitors to
Canada. So, lots of great products here.
So, it looks like they have some type of
investment plans, like financial
advisors, probably mutual funds. And
let's go to banking. I didn't know you
could do banking with Manulife, but now
I do. So, they have a high-interest
savings account, which doesn't look that
high at
.3%.
Uh we have fixed mortgage rates 3.44%
and GICs at 2%. We've got RRSP loans,
investment loans, and line of credit.
You can apply for a 100,000
uh in a line of credit, which would be
nice. Set it up once, then borrow what
you need and pay back what you want. I
wonder what the the percentage is, what
the interest is on that. Which type of
mortgage is right for you? I'm buying a
home, I want to switch or refinance, my
house is paid. I didn't know you could
get a Manulife. I guess it's through
Visa. So, we've got the Manulife money
plus Visa Infinite card. We've got the
Manulife money plus Visa Platinum card.
We've got Okay, tax-free savings
account. We have uh you can do a RRSP
through them and registered retirement
income fund through them. All right, now
let's go over to Sun Life, to their
website and have a look. All right, so
let's look into their products.
Okay, here we go. Exploring products. We
have health insurance, personal health
insurance, critical illness insurance,
long-term care insurance, disability
insurance. We have life insurance
overview, term life insurance, permanent
life insurance, participating life
insurance, and universal life insurance.
We also have travel insurance, mortgage
protection insurance, family insurance,
workplace benefits, affinity markets,
business owner insurance. They have
saving plans, just like Manulife, RRSPs,
TFSAs, and RESPs.
R E S P E C T, find out what it means to
me. Sock it to me, sock it to me, sock
it to me, sock it to me. Okay, GICs and
insurance GICs, mutual funds, segregated
funds, workplace investments, brokerage
services. So, basically, they're the
same. Now, I have two friends. One is a
financial advisor, very very smart man
who loves Manulife. I have a friend who
works at Sun Life and he's highly
trusted, great friend,
and he works there and raves about
Sun Life. So, I see both sides of it. So
now, as a dividend investor, you know,
which is the best one to buy? Now,
here's the thing. So, during the
2008-2009
financial crisis,
Manulife cut their dividend in half.
I did not know that when I bought.
That's a little frightening, especially
now when we have like the fastest stock
market crash in history. What's Manulife
going to do? Are they going to cut my
$13.90 per month in half? I don't like
that.
Now, Sun Life didn't. Okay, so anyways,
let's look at the Manulife cut, the
thing that I I'm scared of. So, we're
going to go down. We're going to scroll
down to 2000, right here, 2009 in Q1.
They cut the dividend from 26 cents a
share. Now, this is probably quarterly.
Yes, that would be quarterly because now
they're up to like they're back up
there, right? So, let's look at that.
2009 Q1. So, 26 cents cut to 13%. They
cut it by 50%
right there. How long did it take them
to get it back up to 26 cents? So, if
you keep scrolling through here, 2012,
2013, 2017,
finally, this quarter, sorry, last
quarter, last year, Q4, they finally got
past 26 cents. So, it took them 10 years
to get it back up to where it was.
So, it's a slow growth dividend for
sure. So, it was at 13 for a long time.
For 5 years, it stayed at 13 cents per
quarter. I don't like that. That's not a
good history. Now, it could be a
different company now.
I know they've grown. Are they going to
do the same thing? Are they going to Is
that in their culture to cut dividends?
Now, if you look at Sun Life, let's go
to the same period, 2009-2008.
So, it was at 34 cents in 2007. 2008, it
was 36 cents. 2009, 36 cents. Now, they
weren't raising it, but they didn't cut
it. That's what we're we're scared of as
dividend investors. 36 cents. So, they
didn't they kept it at 36 cents until
when? Until 2015, right? So, about 6
years after, they started to boost it
up.
And now, it's up to 55 cents. Okay, so I
found out that I was on the wrong Sun
Life thing
on Yahoo Finance. Whoops.
Okay, anyways, I have it proper here.
It's slf.to
because the dividend history didn't add
up where they were paying 55 cents per
quarter. So, they pay $2.20
a year. So, right now the dividend's at
5%.
Um they were at $65
on February 20th. So, 6565.
So, it looks like they're about 30% from
their highs. Uh let's go to Manulife.
Now, this is the right one.
Okay, so let's go. So, on let's go to
February 20th. That's roughly when
things went to things became dire. Let's
go to What price do we got? 2659. Yeah,
so they're down 35% and Sun Life's down
30%. I could be wrong. Correct me if my
math's wrong there, but it looks like
Manulife's been hit more than Sun Life.
Now, is that because people fear that
they're going to cut the dividend like
they did last time? Maybe, I don't know.
See, they could still be getting
punished. I believe Sun Life is at a
premium as far as like price to book and
earnings and everything. I think the
value play is Manulife, but it's that
cutting of the dividend back in 2009,
which I think still hurts them. And the
fact that they haven't really grown
their dividend that much. Well, right
now, you're getting a 6.88%
dividend on Manulife and you're getting
a 5% dividend on Sun Life. Sun Life is
probably a less riskier play because
they haven't cut they don't have a
history of cutting their dividend. So,
which one which ones do you guys think
is the better buy? It's risk versus
reward, always, right? So, I don't know.
They both seem like they're competent
insurance companies. In fact, I may pick
one of those to get insurance very soon.
So, I'll be digging deep and into the
both companies as well as looking at
competitors. So, I don't know which one
As companies, I I think they're both
great companies and there's also other
companies out there. What do you guys
recommend? If you live in Canada or even
the States, I'd like to invest in
American insurance companies as well.
Which insurance company do you
recommend? Who are you using? Do you
guys own either of these stocks that
I've talked about today? I already own
some Manulife. Maybe it's safe to buy
Sun Life to have both competitors. So,
anyways, guys, what do you guys think of
my research? What do you recommend?
Please like and comment below and I will
talk to you guys later. Cheers. Bye.
Hey.